<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS Immersion Day 2021</title>
    <link>http://localhost:80/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AWS Immersion Day 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:80/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/contact_us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/contact_us/</guid>
      <description>This Event and Lab were Delievered by Qlik and AWS Partner Team: AWS Partner Team   Ian Mercer, Global Partner Development Manager - ianmer@amazon.com   Dilip Rajan Park, Partner Solution Architect - rajand@amazon.com   Tony Song Sr. ISV Partner Success Architect - tonysong@amazon.com   Qlik Partner Team   Boris Geller, Head of Strategic Tech BD - boris.geller@qlik.com   Andrew Schwartz, Senior Manager, Global Technology Alliances- andrew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/getting_started/</guid>
      <description>Preface Before beginning with the tutorial we like to tell you that your Qlik and AWS team is there to help you please do not hesitate to reach out.
Before starting tutorial and labs make sure you can log into the following
Connecting to Qlik Replicate Web UI   url:__https://your_host_ip:3552/attunityreplicate/ User Name: admin Password: Aws_immersion123
  For the lab we will not be using a certificate rather we will &amp;lsquo;accept risk and proceed on&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/resources/</guid>
      <description>Resources  Thanks for taking the Qlik Replicate Lab for a spin. Assuming you followed all the steps and completed the exercises, we are confident that you will have found the experience to be a good one and that our focus on ease of use was evident. The product documentation and help can be found at: Qlik Replicate Online Guide - Online Help Guide for Qlik Replicate Qlik Replicate Offline User Guide) - PDF Help Guide for Qlik Replicate Qlik Community - Community page for Qlik Replicate About the Sample Data  The sample data used in this tutorial comes from the Sean Lahman Baseball Archive Copyright 1996-2018 by Sean Lahman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/tutorials/</guid>
      <description>AWS Immersion Day 2021 Tutorials Log In to Qlik Replicate to Start the Tutorial First things first, we need to open Qlik Replicate. Open Replicate in a new tab in your broswer. For host username and password please refer to GettingStarted Page
Please note that you may need to press accept security and proceed for certificate
Once you are logged in you will see the main screen for Qlik Replicate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/videos/</guid>
      <description>Videos  Thanks for taking the Qlik Replicate Lab for a spin. Here are some Video resource for the Labs as well other Video Assets produced by the Qlik Team. The product documentation and help can be found at:   Qlik Replicate Explainer and Demo Video   Qlik Replicate Real Time Data Ingestion   Qlik Replicate Many to One   Qlik Replicate Installation on Linux   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Kafka Messages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/kafka-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/kafka-show/</guid>
      <description>Here are the 200 most recent messages that were delivered to Kafka displayed using the Kafka &amp;ldquo;Console Consumer&amp;rdquo;. Messages are deserialized as raw text, but as you can see the data is in JSON format as we configured in the Replicate task.
 /* Add redirection so we can get stderr. */ $cmd=&amp;quot;/opt/kafka*/bin/kafka-console-consumer.sh --bootstrap-server kafka:29092 --topic testdrive --offset ${offset} --max-messages ${msgcount} --partition 0 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1&amp;quot;; $handle = popen(&amp;quot;$kafkaopts;$cmd&amp;quot;, &#39;r&#39;); while (!feof($handle)) { $output = fread($handle, 2096); echo(nl2br($output)); ob_flush(); flush(); } pclose($handle); ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 1 - MySQL Source Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/db-mysql-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/db-mysql-source/</guid>
      <description>The first thing we need to do is create a source endpoint. We do this by clicking the Manage Endpoint Connections button at the top of the screen.
And you will see this window.
From there, click on Add New Endpoint Connection link or the + New Endpoint Connection button at the top of the screen.
Once you do that you will see this window:
We will now create a MySQL source endpoint:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 1 - MySQL Source Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/kafka-mysql-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/kafka-mysql-source/</guid>
      <description>For this use case, we will simply reuse the MySQL source endpoint that we created in the Database-to-Database use case. If you chose to skip the Database-to-Database use case, that is fine. Simply navigate to the instructions for creating the [MySQL Source Configuration]({{ base }}{% link _replicate/tutorial/db-mysql-source.md %}) in the Database-to-Database use case and then return here to continue with this Kafka use case.
Feel free to Test Connection to ensure that everything is still OK with the MySQL source connection if you wish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 2 - Kafka Target Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/kafka-target/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/kafka-target/</guid>
      <description>Next we need to configure our Kafka target endpoint. The process is much the same as you saw with the endpoints, and once again you will note that the configuration process is context-sensitive as we move along.
As before, the first step in the configuration process is to tell Replicate that we want to create a new endpoint. If you are back on the main window, you will need to click on Manage Endpoint Connections button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 2 - Postgres Target Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/db-postgres-target/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/db-postgres-target/</guid>
      <description>Next we need to configure our Postgres target endpoint. The process is much the same as you saw with the MySQL source, and once again you will note that the configuration process is context-sensitive as we move along.
As before, the first step in the configuration process is to tell Replicate that we want to create a new endpoint. If you are back on the main window, you will need to click on Manage Endpoint Connections button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 3 - Configure Your Task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/db-config-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/db-config-task/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have configured our MySQL source and Postgres target endpoints, we need to tie them together in what we call a Replicate task. In short, a task defines the following:
 A source endpoint A target endpoint The list of tables that we want to capture Any transformations we want to make on the data  To get started, we need to create a task. Click on the + New Task button at the top of the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 3 - Configure Your Task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/kafka-config-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/kafka-config-task/</guid>
      <description>Now that we have configured our MySQL source and Kafka target endpoints, we need to tie them together in what we call a Replicate task. In short, a task defines the following:
 A source endpoint A target endpoint The list of tables that we want to capture Any transformations we want to make on the data  To get started, we need to create a task. Click on the + New Task button at the top of the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 4 - Configure a Transformation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/db-config-xform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/db-config-xform/</guid>
      <description>The transformation we will create in this section will:
 Add a new column fullName to the Player target table Populate that column with values from other columns in the table.  To get started, double click on the Player table in the Selected Tables frame.
Then click on the Transform button.
And click on Add Column.
Call the new column fullName,
and change its default type from STRING(50) to WSTRING(100).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 4 - Run Your Task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/kafka-run-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/kafka-run-task/</guid>
      <description>When you press Run, Replicate will automatically switch from Designer mode to Monitor mode. You will be able to watch the status of the full load as it occurs, and then switch to monitoring change data capture as well.
After Full Load is complete, click on the Completed bar to display the tables. There is DML activity running in the background. Click on the Change Processing tab to see it in action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step 5 - Run Your Task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:80/db-run-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:80/db-run-task/</guid>
      <description>After you press Run, Replicate will automatically switch from Designer mode to Monitor mode. You will be able to watch the status of the full load as it occurs, and then switch to monitoring change data capture as well.
When Full Load is complete, click on the Completed bar to display the tables. There is DML activity running in the background. Click on the Change Processing tab to see it in action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
